Guide to the Eugene O'Neill Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
EO sitting with CMO at end of pool
View of drive
Blemie lying on steps near birdcage
EO standing with CMO, facing each other on steps
EO standing with CMO next to house, with Blemie in foreground
EO standing with CMO in front of tree
EO standing with CMO in woods
EO standing next to CMO next to house
EO standing with CMO on drive
EO standing with CMO on path
EO sitting with unidentified woman on park bench
EO standing with unidentified woman on path, with Blemie in foreground
EO sitting with unidentified woman in field
EO standing with unidentified woman next to house
CMO standing in field, close-up
Two men on three horses in field
CMO standing in field, far away
CMO standing next to pool
Unidentified woman standing in field, far away
View of grounds
CMO standing in field, close-up
Unidentified woman standing in field, close-up
Unidentified woman standing next to Blemie
Unidentified woman kneeling next to Blemie
Ben lying in driveway
Blemie looking toward bushes
CMO sitting with unidentified woman on park bench
CMO sitting on wire chair in front of steps
Two views of grounds
Two views of house
View of grounds (2 versions)
Pool (2 versions)
Two views of grounds
EO wearing [underwear?], sitting next to pool (6 versions)
Two views of flowers
Four views of grounds
Two views of house
One view of grounds
One view of house
EO sitting with unidentified man in deck chairs (8 versions)
Unidentified man sitting on deck chair
Seven views of house
One view of grounds
One view of house
Chauffeur standing next to O'Neills' car
One view of house
EO standing in front of car, with chauffeur to right
Tao House, album #1, 1940 Dec 6, box 115, folder 2121:
Eleven views of house from fields
View of orchard from terrace
Pool
Tao House, album #2, 1941 Jun 26, box 115, folder 2122:
Outside of wall of yard
View of yard from house
View of countryside from house
View inside back yard
Tao House, album #3, 1941 Aug 4, box 115, folder 2123:
Front of house, looking up hill
Walkway
Pool
View outside of wall of yard
Pool
EO on ladder, tacking up jasmine
EO on ladder, tacking up jasmine
Tao House, album #4, 1941 Aug 4, box 115, folder 2124:
View inside back yard (3 versions)
Outbuilding
Pool (2 copies)
View of yard from house
View inside back yard
Tao House, album #g5, 1942 May 3, box 115, folder 2125:
Four views inside back yard
Scrapbook made by Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, [1954?], box 138, folder 2495:
EO standing with Carlotta Monterey O'Neill and black cat in front of valley at Tao House, 1939
Studio portraits by [de Meyer?] of EO sitting at table, looking at camera, [1929 Jul?]
Portrait by Edward Steichen of EO sitting, looking at camera, [1933]
Portrait by Edward Steichen of CMO sitting, from right, with eyes open, [1933]
Two views of grounds at Château du Plessis, [1930]
View of drive at Château du Plessis, [1930]
View of house at Château du Plessis, [1930]
EO standing with CMO in front of tree at Château du Plessis, [1929]
EO standing on porch, wearing Asian robe at Cap-d'Ail, [1929]
EO sitting wearing v-neck sweater next to CMO at Cap-d'Ail, [1929]
EO sitting on step next to Blemie, sitting, at Château du Plessis, [1930]
EO leaning against balcony, side view, at Las Palmas, [1931 Mar]
CMO sitting next to pool at Château du Plessis, [1930]
EO wearing bathing suit, sitting on beach at Guéthary, [1928]
EO wearing bathing suit, sitting on beach next to CMO, looking at her at Beacon Farm, [1931 summer]
EO sitting in Bugatti racing car, in driveway at Château du Plessis, [1930]
CMO wearing shorts sitting on beach at Guéthary, [1928]
EO wearing striped robe, lying on lawn, reading next to Blemie, at Beacon Farm, [1931 summer]
Goldfish pond at Casa Genotta, [1932 Oct]
View of house from beach at Casa Genotta, [193-]
EO sitting on deck chair with Blemie on his lap at Casa Genotta, [1933]
EO leaning back in deck chair at Casa Genotta, [1933]
View of patio at Casa Genotta, [193-]
EO leaning against fence at Wolf Lake, [1934]
EO wearing bathing suit, standing on diving board at Wolf Lake, [1934]
EO sitting in canoe at Wolf Lake, [1934]
EO sitting on deck chair with Blemie on his lap at Casa Genotta, [1933]
EO standing in front of cabinet, smoking at Tao House, [1939]
EO opening up piano, "Rosie" at Tao House, [1939]
EO playing piano, "Rosie," with eyes closed, at Tao House, [1939]
EO playing piano, "Rosie," with eyes open, at Tao House, [1939]
EO playing piano, "Rosie," looking up, at Tao House, [1939]
EO leaning against piano, "Rosie," at Tao House, [1939]
Studio portrait by Ben Pinchot of EO sitting, with CMO leaning against him, [192-]
Portrait by Marcia Stein of CMO looking left, close-up, [192-]
EO leaning on elbow (dark background) in Seattle (Wash.), [1936 Nov]
Debut portrait by Lallie Charles of CMO in London, [1909]
Portrait by F. Roy Kemp at 35 East 84th Street, New York of EO standing on balcony, [1946 Aug 15]
CMO wearing long, print dress, lying in deck chair at Casa Genotta, [1932]
EO on ladder, tacking up jasmine at Tao House, [1941 Aug 4] (3 versions)
EO sitting on stump in garden at Tao House, [1941]
EO sitting on deck chair in garden at Tao House, [1941]
Studio portrait by Nickolas Muray of EO, [1922]
Studio portrait by Nickolas Muray of EO, [1926]
Portrait by Edward Steichen of EO, n.d.
EO sitting on rock writing in notebook, [ca. 1893-94]
Series VI, Memorabilia, Office Material, Stationery
Visiting cards, box 129, folder 2447
"Carlotta Monterey O'Neill" cards
"Eugene O'Neill" cards in Cartier box
"Mr. and Mrs. Eugene O'Neill" cards with envelopes in Cartier box
"Mrs. Eugene O'Neill" cards in Cartier box
Plates for visiting cards, wrapped in Cartier paper, in Arden powder box; box is labeled "Dies" in CMO's hand
Brown leather case [for visiting cards?]
Series VI, Memorabilia, Office Material, Writing Tools
Pen, pencils, erasers, sharpener, and monogram stamp, box 129, folder 2448:
Fountain pen, with tip
Fountain pen tips (12), in paper Esterbrook box
Erace-Rite ink eraser, with brush
Blaisdell Klenzo ink eraser
Monogram stamp, "C" and "E" intertwined
Pencil sharpener, in black case
A. W. Faber "Castell" metal box, containing 12 pencils, one sharpened Eberhard Faber Black Wing paper box, containing nine 602 pencils, seven sharpened
Venus Drawing Pencils paper box, containing ten 3B pencils, one sharpened
Series VI, Memorabilia, Personal Effects Leather jewelry box, box 130, folder 2464:
Upper left tray, upper left compartment:
Set of two brown knotted cord cuff links
Set of two black knotted cord cuff links
Set of two blue and red knotted cord cuff links
Set of two red and white knotted cord cuff links
One blue knotted cord cuff link
One black swirled cord cuff link
One Tiffany and Company purple and yellow cuff link
One purple and yellow screw-on cuff link
Upper left tray, middle left compartment:
One gold chain for watch and keys
Set of two gold "Krementz Plate" collar fasteners
Set of two plain gold collar fasteners
One Tiffany and Company 14K gold collar fastener
One mother-of-pearl and gold "Swank 2 for 25" collar fastener
Set of two gold garter fasteners
Upper left tray, lower left compartment:
One coral cameo, engraved with portrait of Carlotta Monterey O'Neill
One 1924 $20 United States gold coin
Upper left tray, right compartment:
One gold ring, set with brown and green opal
One gold ring, set with fire opal, engraved: "C. to E. 1st year"
Gold ring of Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, engraved on outside: "PORT SAID _ JAN. 15. 29"; engraved on inside: "I AM NOT AS I WAS"
Gold ring of Eugene O'Neill, engraved on outside: "PORT SAID _ JAN. 15. 29"; engraved on inside: "I AM NOT AS I WAS"
Upper right tray, left compartment:
One Cartier ring composed of three circlets
One gold linked ring
One green jade ring
Upper right tray, upper right compartment:
Two cameos of a woman, one in [amber?] set in gold, one in white framed in gold; both cameos in green leather box
Upper right tray, lower right compartment:
One gold cigarette lighter with Dunhill watch set into side, in chamois pouch; lighter engraved: "To Genie - from Carlotta, 7/22/'29."
Lower tray, left compartment:
One gold cigarette case, in chamois pouch; case engraved on outside: "To Gene from Carlotta, 1927"
One set of two black garters with gold clasps; each clasp engraved: "E.O.'N"
One set of two ebony and coral cuff links, in chamois double pouch One stainless steel Morgan pocket watch on platinum-and-pearl chain, in chamois pouch
One Longines wrist watch, with leather strap, engraved on back: "EUGENE O'NEILL"
Lower tray, right compartment:
One porcelain miniature doll
Two Catholic holy medals
One gold collar pin
American literature -- 20th Century -- Archives; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Dramatists, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Nobel Prizes; Playwriting; Pulitzer Prizes; Theater -- United States; Audiovisual materials; Sound recordings; Certificates -- United States -- 20th Century; Checkbooks -- United States -- 20th Century; Diaries -- United States -- 20th Century; Jewelry; Photograph albums; Photographic prints; Postcards; Scrapbooks; Snapshots; Theater programs; Dramatists, American -- 20th Century; Aronberg, Winfield E.; Baldridge, Cyrus Leroy, 1889-1977; Barton, Ralph, 1891-1931; Boulton, Agnes, 1893-1968; Chaplin, Oona, 1925-1991; Clark, Barrett H. (Barrett Harper), 1890-1953; Commins, Saxe, 1892-1958; Covarrubias, Miguel, 1904-1957; Crouse, Russel, 1893-1966; Frueh, Alfred Joseph, 1880-1968; Gelb, Arthur, 1924-2014; Gelb, Barbara, 1926-2017; Gierow, Karl Ragnar, 1904-; Helburn, Theresa, 1887-1959; Jones, Robert Edmond, 1887-1954; Langner, Lawrence, 1890-1962; Macgowan, Kenneth, 1888-1963; Mirlas, León; Nathan, George Jean, 1882-1958; Nichols, Dudley, 1895-1960; O'Neill, Carlotta; O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953 ( Homes and haunts, California); O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953; O'Neill, James, 1847-1920; O'Neill, James, 1878-1923; O'Neill, Mary Ellen Quinlan, 1857-1922; O'Neill, Shane Rudraighe, 1919-1977; Pitt-Smith, Kathleen, 1889-1982; Quintero, José; Schmidt, Lars, 1917-2009; Sheaffer, Louis; Sisk, Robert, 1903-1964; Stram, Cynthia Chapman; Stram, Gerald Eugene; Sze, Mai-mai, 1909-; Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964; Marinoff, Fania, 1890-1971; Weinberger, Harry, 1888-; Cadwalader, Wickersham & Taft; Nutter, McClennen & Fish; Richard J. Madden Play Company, Inc; Yale University Press; Yale University. Library
- Eugene O'Neill Correspondence, 1878-1953; Series I; 5.6; (15 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Eugene O'Neill Correspondence, is organized
  into three subseries: General Correspondence, Family
  Correspondence, and Third Party Correspondence. Each
  subseries is arranged alphabetically by last name. In the
  first subseries, letters from correspondents not listed
  individually may be found in "letter" general files
  unidentified correspondence is arranged at the end.
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - "A" general, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abbey Theatre, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Addressed to W. B. Yeats. Ca. 1934
      Feb 12.
    - Academy of American Poets, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Adams, Franklin P., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1934 Nov 26 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Related Archival Materials note
      See also: Series IV, Personal Papers, Certificates and Awards, box 89, folder 1523
    - American Philosophical Society, [1935] (Box 1, Folder 6)
      See also: Series IV, Personal Papers, Certificates and Awards, box 142, folder 2528
    - American Play Company
      See: Richard J. Madden Play Company, Inc., box 4, folder 151 through box 8, folder 211
    - American-Scandinavian Foundation (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - The American Spectator, 1932 Oct 28 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Encloses two copies of Vol. I, No. 1.
    - Anderson, Sherwood (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Aronberg, Winfield E., 1944-51, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10-12)
      See also: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #2, box 12, folder 302 (1944 Oct 21; 1944 Oct 29; 1944 Dec 21; 1944 Dec 30)
      See also: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #3, box 12, folder 303 ([1945 Feb?]; 1945 Mar 27; 1945 Jul 15)
    - Associated Press, 1930, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Includes draft to Robert Sisk.
    - Association française d'expansion et d'échanges artistiques, 1931 Jan 8 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Atkinson, Brooks, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Authors' League of America, 1946, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - "B" general, 1939-51, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
      See also: Jero Magon, box 2, folder 107
    - Baker, George P., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Baker, Newton Diehl, 1933, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Barletta, Léonidas, 1935 Aug 8 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Barlocco, Jacobo Reinaldo, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Basshe, Em Jo, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Bisch, Louis, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Blackfriars' Guild, 1937 Apr 20 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Bohemian Club (San Francisco, Calif.), [1939 Jul] (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Includes drafts to Richard J. Madden
      Play Company, Inc. and Harry
      Weinberger.
    - Boni & Liveright
      See: Horace Liveright, Inc., box 2, folder 79
    - Bonner, Paul Hyde, [1933 Jul 12] (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Boston University, 1951 Feb 8 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Bourgeois, Maurice, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Brady, William A., 1939 Nov 15 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Brooks, William E., [1934 Mar 5] (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Includes draft to Eddie Cantor.
    - Brown, John Mason, [1939] (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Burnett, Whit
      See: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #2, box 12, folder 301 (1944 Jun 9)
      See: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #3, box 12, folder 303 (1945 Jul 7)
    - "C" general, 1948-53, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 32)
      See also: M. Eleanor Fitzgerald, box 1, folder 59
      See also: Margaret Larkin, box 2, folder 98
      See also: John H. G. Pell, box 3, folders 137-140
    - Canby, Henry Seidel, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Cantor, Eddie
      See: William E. Brooks, box 1, folder 30
    - Carpenter, Frederic Ives
      See: Random House (Firm), box 3, folder 150
      See: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #3, box 12, folder 303 (1945 Mar 24)
    - Catel, Jean, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      Letter dated 1947 Jan 12 encloses
      photograph of his house.
    - Catholic Actors Guild of America, 1934 Feb 7 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      Includes brochure.
    - Cerf, Bennett
      See: Eleanor Flexner, box 2, folder 61
      See: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #3, box 12, folder 303 (1945 Sep 15)
    - Chapman, Edward Mortimer, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Charles Scribner's Sons, [1934], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 37)
      Includes drafts to Shane Rudraighe
      O'Neill, Chard Powers Smith, and
      David Shiel.
    - Chisholm, Erik, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Clark, Barrett Harper, [1935-39], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Includes draft to Mr. Edlund.
      See also: Dramatists Play Service (New York, N.Y.), box 1, folder 52
      See also: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #1, box 12, folder 300 (1944 Apr 27; 1944 May 9)
      See also: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #2, box 12, folder 302 (1944 Dec 15)
    - Clemens, Cyril, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Cohan, George M., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 41)
      Telegrams (drafts) to Cohan and cast
      of Ah, Wilderness!.
    - Comarnescu, Petru, 1947, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 42)
      See also: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #3, box 12, folder 303 (1945 Jul 12)
    - Commins, Saxe, 1933, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 43)
      See also: Philip Dunning, box 1, folder 53
      See also: Horace Liveright, Inc., box 2, folder 79
      See also: Random House (Firm), box 3, folder 150
      See also: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #2, box 12, folders 301-302 (1944 Jul 12; 1944 Dec 14)
    - Corn Exchange Bank Trust Company, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Crouse, Russel, 1934-53, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - "D" general, 1933-51, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 46)
      See also: Will Rogers, box 8, folder 213
    - Dazey, Charles Turner, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Deeter, Jasper, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Dodd, Lee Wilson, [ca. 1932] (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Dodd, Mead & Company, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Dowd, Harrison, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Dramatiska teatern (Stockholm, Sweden)
      See: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #3, box 12, folder 303 (1945 Feb 18)
    - Dramatists Play Service (New York, N.Y.), 1948-53 (Box 1, Folder 52)
      Includes letters from Barrett Harper
      Clark.
    - Dunning, Philip, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 53)
      Includes drafts to Saxe Commins and
      J. B. Havre (i.e., "Dad").
    - "E" general, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 54)
      See also: Barrett Harper Clark, box 1, folder 39
    - Ernst, Cane & Berner, 1948-53 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - "F" general, 1936-51, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Fadiman, Clifton, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 57)
      Includes drafts to Mr. Lowry and
      Aline MacMahon.
    - Fierro Blanco, Antonio de, 1934 Aug 30 (Box 1, Folder 58)
      Introduced by letter from Walter G.
      de Steiguer.
    - Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 59)
      Includes drafts to Lillian Brennan
      and Mr. Chamburn.
    - Flanagan, Hallie, 1951, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Flexner, Eleanor, 1938, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 61)
      Includes draft to Bennett Cerf.
    - Frederick A. Stokes Company, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Freedley, George, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Frueh, Alfred Joseph, 1946 Nov 22 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Fuller, Edmund (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - "G" general, 1934-51, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Galvao, Henrique, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 67)
      See also: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #3, box 12, folder 303 (1945 Feb 4; 1945 May 30)
    - Goodman, Edward, [1936 Dec 7] (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Grovas, María de la Luz, [1936] (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1934-51, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 70)
      See also: Donald Pace, box 3, folder 135
      See also: Series IV, Personal Papers, Financial and Legal Material, box 102, folders 1694-1700; box 103, folders 1701-1709
    - "H" general, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 71)
      See also: Léon Mirlas, box 2, folder 111
    - Hamilton, Clayton Meeker, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Hatchards (Firm), 1945 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Hauptmann, Gerhart, 1932 Mar 18 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Havre, J. B.
      See: Philip Dunning, box 1, folder 53
      See: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #2, box 12, folder 302 (1944 Dec 12)
    - Havre, Paralee, 1951-53, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Heidt, Joe, [1938-39], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 76)
      Includes draft to Richard J. Madden
      Play Company, Inc.
    - Helburn, Theresa, [1936-39], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 77)
      Includes drafts to Mr. Piazzi, Harry
      Weinberger, and Mr. Witkin.
      See also: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #2, box 12, folder 301 (1944 Jun 16)
    - Hopkins, Arthur, 1926, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 78)
      Includes draft to Jane Rubin.
      See also: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #1, box 12, folder 300 (1944 Jun 5)
      See also: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #2, box 12, folder 302 (1944 Oct 1)
    - Horace Liveright, Inc., 1928-32 (Box 2, Folder 79)
      Includes Boni & Liveright
      correspondence and letters from Saxe
      Commins.
      See also: Notes and drawings for Dynamo, box 51, folder 1040
    - Horton, Philip, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 80)
      Includes draft to Poetry Society of
      Georgia.
    - Howard, Sidney Coe, 1936, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Inoué, Sôji, 1951, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 82)
      See also: Eiji Ishida, box 2, folder 83
    - Ishida, Eiji, [1938]-53 (Box 2, Folder 83)
      Includes draft to Eiji Ishida and
      Sôji Inoué.
    - Ishill, Joseph
      See also: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #1, box 12, folder 300 (1944 May 9)
    - "J" general, 1951, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - J. Walter Thompson Company, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Jones, Robert Edmond, [1938], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 86)
      See also: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #1, box 12, folder 300 (1944 Apr 9)
      See also: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #2, box 12, folder 301 (1944 Jun 9; 1944 Jul 2)
      See also: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #3, box 12, folder 303 (1945 Aug 21)
    - Josephson, Lennart Hjalmar, 1952-53 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Joy, Nicholas, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - "K" general, 1942, 1951, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Klopfer, Donald, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Koischwitz, Otto, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 91)
      Includes draft to George Jean Nathan.
    - Kozol, Harry L., 1951-52 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Krutch, Joseph Wood, 1939, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - "L" general, 1931-38, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 94)
      See also: Samuel French, Inc., box 8, folder 216
    - Labarthe, Pedro Juan
    - Lagerlöf, Selma, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 95)
      Includes draft to Mr. Swenson.
    - Langner, Lawrence, 1934-38, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 96)
      See also: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #1, box 12, folder 300 (1944 May 13)
      See also: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #2, box 12, folder 302 (1945 Jan 22)
      See also: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #3, box 12, folder 303 (1945 Apr 12)
    - Lanux, Pierre Combret de, [1937, 1938] (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Larkin, Margaret, [1935], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 98)
      Includes drafts to Mr. Conklin and
      Lee Simonson.
    - Laufer, Beatrice, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Lerner, Max, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Lewis, Sinclair, [1936 Nov 25] (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Lowry, Robert
      See: Clifton Fadiman, box 1, folder 57
    - "M" general, 1935-38, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 102)
      See also: Clifton Fadiman, box 1, folder 57
    - McBean, Angus, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - McGee, Harold, [1934-38] (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - Macgowan, Kenneth, 1933-51 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Macy, George, [1938] (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Madden, Richard J.
    - Magon, Jero, [1939], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 107)
      Includes drafts to Mr. Beachboard and
      National Association of Audubon
      Societies for the Protection of Wild
      Birds and Animals.
    - Manning, Hugo, 1950 Jun 20 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Middleton, George, 1951 Feb 7 (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Miller, Arthur, 1949 Feb 22 (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Mirlas, Léon, 1934-49, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 111)
      Includes drafts to Mr. Huggins,
      Richard J. Madden Play Company, Inc.,
      and Mr. River.
      See also: Drafts of letters, holograph, in notebook #2, box 12, folder 302 (1944 Oct 19)
    - Moeller, Philip, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - Munsell, Warren, [1934-35], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 113)
      Includes draft to [Mr.?] Smith.
    - Museum of the City of New York, 1932-49 (Box 2, Folder 114)
      Includes correspondence with May
      Davenport Seymour.
    - "N" general, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Nagle, Urban, 1937 Apr 27 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Nathan, George Jean, 1931-52, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 117)
      See also: Otto Koischwitz, box 2, folder 91
    - National Association of Audubon Societies for the Protection of Wild Birds and Animals
      See: Jero Magon, box 2, folder 107
    - Neergaard, Arthur Edwin, 1937 Mar 2 (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Neuberger, Richard L., [1936 Dec] (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - The New York Times, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - Nichols, Dudley, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 121)
      Letter dated 1947 Apr 13 encloses
      panoramic photograph from Mourning Becomes Electra.
      For photographs sent by Dudley
      Nichols from motion picture of Mourning Becomes Electra, see:
      Box 123, folder 2340 through box 126,
      folder 2392
    - Nichols, Lewis, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 122)